<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<EndpointDescription xmlns="http://clarin.eu/fcs/endpoint-description"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://clarin.eu/fcs/endpoint-description ../../schema/Core_2/Endpoint-Description.xsd"
	version="2">
	<Capabilities>
		<Capability>http://clarin.eu/fcs/capability/basic-search</Capability>
		<Capability>http://clarin.eu/fcs/capability/advanced-search</Capability>
	</Capabilities>
	<SupportedDataViews>
		<SupportedDataView id="hits" delivery-policy="send-by-default"
			>application/x-clarin-fcs-hits+xml</SupportedDataView>
		<SupportedDataView id="adv" delivery-policy="send-by-default"
			>application/x-clarin-fcs-adv+xml</SupportedDataView>
		<SupportedDataView id="cmdi" delivery-policy="need-to-request"
			>application/x-cmdi+xml</SupportedDataView>
	</SupportedDataViews>
	<SupportedLayers>
		<SupportedLayer id="word" result-id="http://spraakbanken.gu.se/ns/fcs/layer/word"
			>text</SupportedLayer>
		<SupportedLayer id="lemma" result-id="http://spraakbanken.gu.se/ns/fcs/layer/lemma"
			>lemma</SupportedLayer>
		<SupportedLayer id="pos" result-id="http://spraakbanken.gu.se/ns/fcs/layer/pos"
			>pos</SupportedLayer>
	</SupportedLayers>

	<Resources>

		<Resource pid="opensonar">
			<Title xml:lang="nl">OpenSoNaR</Title>
			<Title xml:lang="en">OpenSoNaR</Title>
			<Description xml:lang="nl">Het meer dan 500 miljoen woorden bevattende
				SoNAR-referentiecorpus, ontwikkeld in het STEVIN-programma onder auspiciën van de
				Nederlandse Taalunie</Description>
			<Description xml:lang="en">The over 500 million word Dutch reference corpus SoNaR
				developed within the STEVIN programme under the aegis of the Dutch Language
				Union.</Description>
			<LandingPageURI>http://opensonar.ato.inl.nl/</LandingPageURI>
			<Languages>
				<Language>nld</Language>
			</Languages>
			<AvailableDataViews ref="hits adv"/>
			<AvailableLayers ref="word lemma pos"/>
		</Resource>

		<Resource pid="chn">
			<Title xml:lang="nl">Corpus Hedendaags Nederlands</Title>
			<Title xml:lang="en">Corpus of Contemporary Dutch</Title>
			<Description xml:lang="nl">Het Corpus Hedendaags Nederlands van het INT.</Description>
			<Description xml:lang="en">A corpus of modern Dutch, containing more than 800,000 texts
				taken from newspapers, books, magazines, news broadcasts and legal writings. The
				corpus is a combination of the 5, 27 and 38 Million Words Corpora and the PAROLE
				Corpus, supplemented with more recent material from the Netherlands, Flanders,
				Surinam and the Netherlands Antilles. </Description>
			<LandingPageURI>http://corpushedendaagsnederlands.inl.nl/</LandingPageURI>
			<Languages>
				<Language>nld</Language>
			</Languages>
			<AvailableDataViews ref="hits adv"/>
			<AvailableLayers ref="word lemma pos"/>
		</Resource>

		<Resource pid="zeebrieven">
			<Title xml:lang="nl">Brieven als Buit</Title>
			<Title xml:lang="en">Letters as Loot</Title>
			<Description xml:lang="nl">Dit corpus bevat brieven uit de 17e en 18e eeuw, geschreven
				door zeevarenden en hun familie en bekenden, maar terechtgekomen bij de Engelsen na
				kaping van de schepen in een van de vier oorlogen die Groot-Brittanië en de
				Republiek der Zeven Verenigde Nederlanden in de 17e en 18e eeuw hebben gevoerd. Het
				corpus bevat een selectie uit deze brieven, ook wel als Sailing Letters of Prize
				Papers bekend, en is gemaakt in het Letters as Loot project o.l.v. Prof. dr. M. van
				der Wal.</Description>
			<Description xml:lang="en">This corpus contains letters from the 17th and 18th century,
				written by sailors, their relatives and acquaintances. They were taken as loot by
				privateers during one of the four wars between Great Britain and the Dutch Republic
				in the 17th and 18th Century and ended up in the National Archives in Kew. This
				corpus contains a selection of these letters and was built in the Letters as Loot
				project of Prof. dr. M. van der Wal.</Description>
			<LandingPageURI>http://brievenalsbuit.inl.nl/</LandingPageURI>
			<Languages>
				<Language>nld</Language>
			</Languages>
			<AvailableDataViews ref="hits adv"/>
			<AvailableLayers ref="word lemma pos"/>
		</Resource>

		<Resource pid="gysseling">
			<Title xml:lang="nl">Corpus Gysseling</Title>
			<Title xml:lang="en">Corpus Gysseling</Title>
			<Description xml:lang="nl">Het Corpus Gysseling bestaat uit de verzameling van alle
				dertiende-eeuwse teksten die als bronmateriaal voor het Vroegmiddelnederlands
				woordenboek hebben gediend. Het is de digitale editie, verrijkt met woord en lemma,
				van het dertiende-eeuwse materiaal uit het Corpus van de Middelnederlandse teksten
				(tot het jaar 1300), uitgegeven in de periode van 1977 tot 1987 door de Gentse
				taalkundige Maurits Gysseling.</Description>
			<Description xml:lang="en">The Corpus Gysseling consists of the collection of all
				thirteenth-century texts that have served as source material for the Early Middle
				Dutch Dictionary. It is the digital edition, enriched with part of speech and lemma,
				of the thirteenth-century material from the Corpus of Middle Dutch texts (until the
				year 1300), issued in the period from 1977 to 1987 by the Ghent linguist Maurits
				Gysseling.</Description>
			<LandingPageURI>http://gysseling.corpus.taalbanknederlands.inl.nl/</LandingPageURI>
			<Languages>
				<Language>nld</Language>
			</Languages>
			<AvailableDataViews ref="hits adv"/>
			<AvailableLayers ref="word lemma pos"/>
		</Resource>

		<Resource pid="nederlab">
			<Title xml:lang="nl">Nederlab (Meertens Instituut)</Title>
			<Title xml:lang="en">Nederlab (Meertens Institute)</Title>
			<Description xml:lang="nl">Van het vroegste Middelnederlands tot Nederlands uit de
				eenentwintigste eeuw. In onderzoeksportaal Nederlab zijn miljoenen oude en nieuwe
				teksten voor het eerst op één plek doorzoekbaar gemaakt voor taalkundigen,
				letterkundigen, historici en cultuurwetenschappers. 41 miljoen tekstdocumenten, 18
				miljard woorden; op uniforme wijze beschikbaar Kranten, romans, bijbelteksten,
				dagboek- fragmenten, briefwisselingen, oorkonden, gebeden en meer. De teksten zijn
				taalkundig verrijkt en doorzoekbaar op onder meer lemma en woordsoort.</Description>
			<Description xml:lang="en">From the earliest Middle Dutch to Dutch from the twenty-first
				century. In the Nederlab research portal, millions of old and new texts have been
				made searchable for linguists, literary experts, historians and cultural scientists
				for the first time in one place. 41 million text documents, 18 billion words;
				Newspapers, novels, biblical texts, diary fragments,
				correspondence, charters, prayers and more. From the collections of scientific and
				heritage institutions Advanced search and analysis options, statistics and
				visualisations. The texts are linguistically annotated and can be search, a.o.,
				on lemma and part of speech.</Description>
			<LandingPageURI>http://www.nederlab.nl/onderzoeksportaal/</LandingPageURI>
			<Languages>
				<Language>nld</Language>
			</Languages>
			<AvailableDataViews ref="hits adv"/>
			<AvailableLayers ref="word lemma pos"/>
		</Resource>
	</Resources>
</EndpointDescription>
